Guide to the Benjamin Everett Jordan Papers, 1896-1974 and undated RL.00651
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Committee Files, 1958-1972
  - Agriculture and Forestry
    - Bills: 92nd Congress (H.R.1163 and others/Commodity Reserves), 1971-1972 Feb., 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Bills: 92nd Congress (H.R.3146-H.R.9634), 1971-1972 (Box 30)
    - Bills: 92nd Congress (H.R.10729/Pesticides-H.R.18582), 1971-1972 (Box 30)
  - Public Works
    - General, 1958-1972, 3 folders (Box 31)
    - Air and Water Pollution Subcommittee, 1967-1969, 2 folders (Box 31)
    - Air and Water Pollution Subcommittee, 1970-1972, 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Flood Control/Rivers and Harbors Subcommittee, 1958-1972, 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Public Buildings and Grounds Subcommittee, 1959-1967, 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Public Buildings and Grounds Subcommittee, 1968-1972 (Box 33)
    - Roads Subcommittee, 1963-1972, 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Rules and Administration (Box 33)
    - General, 1959-1964, 6 folders (Box 34)
    - General, 1965-1971, Oct., 7 folders (Box 35)
    - General, 1971, Nov. - 1972 (Box 36)
    - Baker Investigation (Congressional Record extracts) 1963 Nov.- 1966, 3 folders (Box 36)
    - Baker Investigation (Bills and Reports), 1963-1967 (Box 36)
    - Baker Investigation (Statements and Press Releases), 1963-1965 (Box 36)
    - Baker Investigation (Committee Correspondence), 1963-1965 (Box 36)
    - Baker Investigation (Constituent and Out-of-State Correspondence), 1963-1966, 4 folders (Box 37)
    - Baker Investigation (Articles and misc.), 1958, 1964 (Box 37)
    - Rule 22, 1958-1971 (Box 37)
    - Seniority, 1971 (Box 37)
    - Veterans, 1962-1964 (Box 38)
    - Bills: 86th Congress (S.Res. 19/Veterans), 1959-1960, 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Bills: 86th Congress (H.R. 519/Depository Libraries), 1959 (Box 38)
    - Bills: 87th Congress (S.2029/Depository Libraries), 1962, 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Bills: 88th Congress (S.Res. 19/Alcoholic Beverages), 1963-1964 (Box 38)
    - Bills: 90th Congress (S.Res 150), 1967 (Box 38)
    - Bills: 92nd Congress (S.382 and others)/Campaign Spending), 1971-1972, 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Bills: 92nd Congress (H.R. 15276/Campaign Spending), 1972 (Box 39)
  - Joint, Special, and Select Committees
    - Atomic Energy Committee, 1961-1972 (Box 39)
    - Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies, 1964-1965, 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Joint Committee on the Library of Congress, 1963-1971, 2 folders (Box 40)
    - Joint Committee on Organization of Congress, 1966-1972 (Box 40)
    - Joint Committee on Printing, 1964-1972, 2 folders (Box 40)
    - Select Committee on Nutrition and Human Needs, 1969-1971 (Box 40)
    - Select Committee on Small Business, 1959, 1969-1972 (Box 40)
    - Special and Select Committees, General, 1966-1967, 1969-1972 (Box 40)
- Subject Files, 1936-1973
  Divided into seventeen subseries which contain mainly constituent correspondence, with some letters from other Congressmen and Congressional staff, as well as background material on some issues. Arranged alphabetically by broad topic, subdivided by more specific topics, then chronologically within each division. Except for Agriculture and Forestry, Foreign Relations, and Public Works, which were retained virtually intact, the files have been sampled, with a retention rate of between 10% and 35%.
  - Aeronautics and Space Sciences
    - General, 1960-1971 (Box 41)
  - Agriculture and Forestry, 1958-1972, 12 boxes
    About 1/3 of the files are devoted to cotton and tobacco, evenly split between them. Rural electrification and farm programs are other prominent topics. Much related material is found in the Agriculture and Forestry Committee files.
    - General, 1958-1962, 6 folders (Box 41)
    - General, 1963-1966, 5 folders (Box 42)
    - General, 1967-1968 May, 5 folders (Box 43)
    - General, 1968 June- 1969, 5 folders (Box 44)
    - General, 1970, 5 folders (Box 45)
    - General, 1971-1972 May, 5 folders (Box 46)
    - General, 1972 June-Dec., 2 folders (Box 47)
    - Commodity Reserves, 1968 Feb.-July, 2 folders (Box 47)
    - Cotton, 1958 May- 1962, 3 folders (Box 47)
    - Cotton, 1963-1965, 5 folders (Box 48)
    - Cotton, 1966-1972, 2 folders (Box 49)
    - Farm Program, 1958-1962 May, 4 folders (Box 49)
    - Farm Program, 1962 June- 1963 (Box 50)
    - REA, 1966-1967, 4 folders (Box 50)
    - Tobacco, 1958-1965 Mar. 3, 5 folders (Box 51)
    - Tobacco, 1965 Mar. 4- 1972, 4 folders (Box 52)
    - Tobacco Research, 1963-1966 (Box 52)
    - Wheat, 1959-1965 (Box 52)
  - Appropriations, 1958-1972, 3-1/2 boxes
    Topics include federal spending and deficits; materials document Jordan's interest in funding libraries, agriculture, medical research, and education.
    - General, 1958-1968, 4 folders (Box 53)
    - General, 1969-1972, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Agriculture, 1966-1972, 3 folders (Box 54)
    - Education, 1968-1972, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Federal Spending, 1967-1972, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Health, Education, and Welfare, 1969-1970 May (Box 55)
    - Health, Education, and Welfare, 1970 June- 1972, 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Supersonic Transport (SST), 1971 (Box 56)
  - Armed Services, 1958-1972, circa 2 boxes
    Highest proportion of mail is from military personnel and families about Army pay and pensions; other topics include the draft and ABM.
    - General, 1958-1964, 2 folders (Box 56)
    - General, 1965-1972, 3 folders (Box 57)
    - Anti-Ballistic Missile (ABM), 1969-1970, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Draft, 1967, 1969-1972, 2 folders (Box 58)
  - Banking and Currency, 1958-72, circa 2 boxes
    Correspondence mainly from the business community on specific banking and insurance bills, housing, federal loans to Lockheed Corp. (1971), and documenting general concern (1966+) about economic problems and inflation.
    - General, 1958-1966 July, 3 folders (Box 58)
    - General, 1966 Aug.- 1972, 3 folders (Box 59)
    - Bank Holding, 1969-1970 (Box 59)
    - Housing, 1958-1962, 1964-1966 (Box 59)
    - Housing, 1967-1972, 2 folders (Box 60)
  - Commerce, 1962-1972, 1-1/2 boxes
    Topics include gun control, cigarette health warnings, pornography, environment, consumer protection, and transportation.
    - General, 1962-1967, 3 folders (Box 60)
    - General, 1968-1972, 3 folders (Box 61)
    - Consumer Subcommittee, 1968-1972 (Box 61)
    - No-fault Insurance, 1971 (Box 61)
    - Supersonic Transport (SST), 1971 (Box 61)
    - Transportation, 1963-1964, 1972 (Box 62)
  - District of Columbia, 1958-1972, 1 folder
    - General, 1958-1972 (Box 62)
  - Finance, 1958-1972, 8-1/2 boxes
    Includes files on taxation, tariffs, welfare measures including Medicare and especially Social Security.
    - General, 1958-1960 June, 3 folders (Box 62)
    - General, 1960 July-1968 May, 5 folders (Box 63)
    - General, 1968 June- 1972, 5 folders (Box 64)
    - Excise Taxes, 1958 1960-1970, 3 folders (Box 65)
    - Family Assistance, 1970-1971 (Box 65)
    - Imports, 1967-1972, 2 folders (Box 65)
    - Income Tax, 1958, 1960-1970, 3 folders (Box 66)
    - Medicare, 1963-1972, 2 folders (Box 66)
    - President's Economy, 1971-1972 (Box 67)
    - Reciprocal Trade, 1958-1964, 2 folders (Box 67)
    - Revenue Sharing, 1971-1972 (Box 67)
    - Social Security, 1958-1960, 2 folders (Box 67)
    - Social Security, 1961-1965, 5 folders (Box 68)
    - Social Security, 1966-1972, 2 folders (Box 69)
    - Taxation, 1959-1966, 1969 Jan.-Oct., 3 folders (Box 69)
    - Taxation, 1969 Nov.- 1972 (Box 70)
    - Tax Cut, 1962-1964 (Box 70)
    - Unemployment Compensation, 1958, 1966 (Box 70)
    - Veterans, 1959-1972, 3 folders (Box 70)
  - Foreign Relations, 1958-1972, 46 boxes
    Two thirds of material relates to the war in Southeast Asia (1965-1972), with the remainder divided among virtually all the other foreign relations issues of the era.
    - General, 1958-1961 July, 6 folders (Box 71)
    - General, 1961 Aug.-1963 June, 5 folders (Box 72)
    - General, 1963 July-1963 Sept. 12, 5 folders (Box 73)
    - General, 1963 Sept. 12-1967 March, 6 folders (Box 74)
    - General, 1965-1967 Mar., 5 folders (Box 75)
    - General, 1967 Apr.-1968 Aug., 6 folders (Box 76)
    - General, 1968 Sept.-1970 June, 6 folders (Box 77)
    - General, 1970 July-1972 Oct., 5 folders (Box 78)
    - China, 1971 (Box 78)
    - Drug Traffic, 1971 (Box 79)
    - Foreign Aid, 1959-1962, 4 folders (Box 79)
    - Foreign Aid, 1963-1970, 5 folders (Box 80)
    - Foreign Aid, 1971 Jan.-1972 Aug., 3 folders (Box 81)
    - Genocide Convention, 1970 Feb.-Nov., 2 folders (Box 81)
    - Genocide Convention, 1970 Dec.- 1972, 4 folders (Box 82)
    - Mutual Security, 1958-1961 (Box 82)
    - Nuclear Non-proliferation Treaty, 1969 (Box 82)
    - Panama Canal, 1964-1966, 1971 (Box 83)
    - Peace Corps, 1961 (Box 83)
    - Southeast Asia, 1965-1966 Jan., 4 folders (Box 83)
    - Southeast Asia, 1966 Feb.-June, 6 folders (Box 84)
    - Southeast Asia, 1966 July-1967 June, 6 folders (Box 85)
    - Southeast Asia, 1967 July-Oct., 6 folders (Box 86)
    - Southeast Asia, 1967 Nov.-1968 Mar. 21, 6 folders (Box 87)
    - Southeast Asia, 1968 Mar. 22-1969 Apr., 7 folders (Box 88)
    - Southeast Asia, 1969 May-Oct., 6 folders (Box 89)
    - Southeast Asia, 1969 Nov.-Dec., 4 folders (Box 90)
    - Southeast Asia (Chapel Hill Vigil), 1969-1972 (Box 90)
    - Southeast Asia, 1970 Jan.-Apr., 3 folders (Box 91)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War, 1970 May 1-8, 3 folders (Box 91)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War, 1970 May 9-15, 5 folders (Box 92)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War, 1970 May 16-20, 6 folders (Box 93)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War, 1970 May 20-25, 7 folders (Box 94)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War, 1970 May 25, 4 folders (Box 95)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War (North Carolina Petitions), 1970 May (Box 95)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War (Out-of-State Petitions), 1970 May (Box 95)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War (Kent State), 1970 May, 2 folders (Box 96)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War, 1970 June 1-5, 4 folders (Box 96)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War (Durham form letters), 1970 June 15-16 (Box 97)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War, 1970 June 15-18 (Box 97)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War (Byrd Amendment), 1970 June 18-19 (Box 97)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War, 1970 June 19-24 (Box 97)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War (The Vietnam Myths), 1970 June 22 (Box 97)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War (Byrd Amendment), 1970 June 22 (Box 97)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War (Byrd Amendment), 1970 June 22-30, 2 folders (Box 98)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War, 1970 June 25-July 2 (Box 98)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War (Out-of-state letters) 1970 July 3-4, 3 folders (Box 98)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War (Out-of-state letters), 1970 July 4-23, 3 folders (Box 99)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War, 1970 July 3-23, 3 folders (Box 99)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War 1970 July 24-Oct. 31, 5 folders (Box 100)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War, 1970 Nov.-1971 Jan. (Box 101)
    - Southeast Asia: Pro-Administration Policy, 1970 May 1-25, 4 folders (Box 101)
    - Southeast Asia: Pro-Administration Policy, 1970 May 25-June 3, 5 folders (Box 102)
    - Southeast Asia: Pro-Administration Policy, 1970 June 4-25, 5 folders (Box 103)
    - Southeast Asia: Pro-Administration Policy, 1970 June 26-Dec., 3 folders (Box 104)
    - Southeast Asia 1971 Feb.-Mar. 23 (3 fodlers) (Box 104)
    - Southeast Asia 1971 Mar. 24-June 8, 6 folders (Box 105)
    - Southeast Asia 1971 June 9-21, 5 folders (Box 106)
    - Southeast Asia 1971 June 22-Aug., 5 folders (Box 107)
    - Southeast Asia 1971 Sept.- 1972, 6 folders (Box 108)
    - Southeast Asia 1972 Mar-May, 5 folders (Box 109)
    - Southeast Asia 1972 June-Aug., 3 folders (Box 110)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War, 1972 June 5, 2 folders (Box 110)
    - Southeast Asia: Anti-War, 1972 June 5 (Box 111)
    - Southeast Asia: Pro-Administration Policy, 1972 June 5 (Box 111)
    - Southeast Asia, 1972 Sept.-1973 Jan. (Box 111)
    - Southeast Asia: Prisoners of War, 1970-1971 Apr., 3 folders (Box 111)
    - Southeast Asia: Prisoners of War, 1971 May- 1972, 2 folders (Box 112)
    - Southeast Asia: Individuals' Correspondence (Dr. N.A. Coulter), 1970-1972 (Box 112)
    - Southeast Asia: Individuals' Correspondence (Gulick Family), 1970-1972 (Box 112)
    - Southeast Asia: Individuals' Correspondence (Hugh Hester), 1970-1971 (Box 112)
    - Southeast Asia: Individuals' Correspondence (Frazier T. Woolard), 1969-1971 (Box 112)
    - Southeast Asia: Clippings, 1968-1971 (Box 112)
    - Southeast Asia: Remarks and Miscellaneous, 1968-1972 (Box 112)
    - Southeast Asia: Reports, Documents, Articles, 1970 May-Sept., 2 folders (Box 113)
    - United Nations, 1961 (Box 113)
    - United Nations, 1962-1971 Nov. 2, 5 folders (Box 114)
    - United Nations, 1971 Nov. 2- 1972 (Box 115)
    - U.S.- USSR Consular Treaty, 1965 Aug.-1967 Feb. 15, 5 folders (Box 115)
    - U.S.-USSR Consular Treaty, 1967 Feb. 16-Aug. 8, 5 folders (Box 116)
  - Government Operations, 1958-1972, 4 folders
    Topics covered briefly include the establishment of several Federal agencies, the NLRB, federal surplus property, with a separate folder on the urban riots of 1967-1970.
    - General, 1958-1972, 3 folders (Box 117)
    - Riots, 1967-1970 (Box 117)
  - House of Representatives Miscellaneous Legislation, 1964, 1966-1967, 1970, 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Legislation, 1964, 1966-1967, 1970 (Box 117)
  - Interior and Insular Affairs, 1958-1965, 1967-1972, 5 folders
    Includes material on national parks, land and water resource management, American Indians. Topics of regional interest include extension of the Blue Ridge Parkway and Cherokee and Lumbee Indian tribes.
    - General, 1958-1965, 1967-1972, 5 folders (Box 118)
  - Interstate and Foreign Commerce, 1958-1962, 5 folders
    Contains material of regional interest on trucking, timber, and textile imports.
    - General, 1958-1962, 3 folders (Box 119)
    - Transportation, 1958-1961 (Box 119)
    - Import-Export, 1959-1962 (Box 119)
  - Judiciary, 1958-1972, 12 boxes
    Most voluminous files are civil rights and gun control. Other issues include school prayer, Equal Rights Amendment, "freedom of choice" (against school bussing), crime, and Electoral College reform.
    - General, 1958-1961, 6 folders (Box 120)
    - General, 1962-1965 Feb., 5 folders (Box 121)
    - General, 1965 Mar.- 1966, 5 folders (Box 122)
    - General, 1967-1968 Sept., 5 folders (Box 123)
    - General, 1968 Oct.-1970 Mar., 5 folders (Box 124)
    - General, 1970 Apr.- 1972, 5 folders (Box 125)
    - Bussing, 1970 (Box 126)
    - Civil Rights, 1958-1963 Sept., 4 folders (Box 126)
    - Civil Rights, 1963 Oct.-1964 Apr. 16, 5 folders (Box 127)
    - Civil Rights, 1964 Apr. 17-Dec., 4 folders (Box 128)
    - Civil Rights (Sample of unanswered out-of-state mail), 1964 (Box 128)
    - Civil Rights, 1965-1967, 5 folders (Box 129)
    - Civil Rights, 1968-1970, 3 folders (Box 130)
    - Crime, 1967-1972 (Box 130)
    - Electoral College Reform, 1969-1972 (Box 130)
    - Equal Rights Amendment, 1970-1972 (Box 130)
    - Gun Control, 1965-1972, 2 folders (Box 131)
    - Preyer School Bill (H.R. 16484), 1970 (Box 131)
    - School Prayer Amendment, 1966-1972 (Box 131)
  - Labor and Public Welfare, 1958-1972, circa 7-1/2 boxes
    Almost half the folders document labor union topics; the rest of the subseries covers a wide variety of topics briefly.
    - General, 1958 (Box 131)
    - General, 1959-1963 May, 5 folders (Box 132)
    - General, 1963 June- 1966, 5 folders (Box 133)
    - General, 1967-1970 Oct., 5 folders (Box 134)
    - General, 1970 Nov.- 1972, 5 folders (Box 135)
    - Animal Research, 1963-1971 (Box 136)
    - Bussing, 1972 (Box 136)
    - Cancer Research, 1971-1972 (Box 136)
    - Federal Aid to Education, 1958-1971, 2 folders (Box 136)
    - Health and Safety, 1968-1972 (Box 136)
    - Labor Management, 1960-1968, 1970-1972, 4 folders (Box 137)
    - Labor Reform, 1959 Jan.-July (Box 137)
    - Labor Reform, 1959 Aug.-Dec. (Box 138)
    - Minimum Wage, 1959-1961, 1966-1972, 2 folders (Box 138)
    - Population, 1971-1972 (Box 138)
    - Poverty, 1964, 1968-1969 (Box 138)
    - Public Welfare, 1958-1960, 1969-1970 (Box 138)
    - Railroads, 1958-1961, 1970-1972 (Box 138)
    - Veterans, 1960-1972 (Box 139)
    - Wages and Hours, 1964-1966 (Box 139)
  - Post Office and Civil Service, 1958-1972, circa 2 boxes
    Primarily correspondence from postal employees and unions concerning pay and retirement benefits. Also documents efforts to adjust postal rates and Jordan's opposition to a 1970 postal reform bill.
    - General, 1958-1962, 3 folders (Box 139)
    - General, 1963-1972, 4 folders (Box 140)
    - Pay Raises, 1958-1972 (Box 140)
    - Retirement, 1958-1972, 3 folders (Box 141)
  - Public Works, 1958-1972, 43 boxes
    Over half the material is devoted to flood control and navigation projects, of which the most fully documented is the Cape Fear River Basin. Other topics include protection and enhancement of coastal areas, pollution, and roads.
    - General, 1958-1967, 5 folders (Box 142)
    - General, 1968-1970 July, 5 folders (Box 143)
    - General, 1970 Aug.-1972 Sept., 5 folders (Box 144)
    - General, 1972 Oct.-Dec. (Box 145)
    - Appalachia/Poverty, 1964-1965 (Box 145)
    - Beach Erosion and Hurricane Protection: General, 1946- 1964, 1971-1972 (Box 145)
    - Beach Erosion and Hurricane Protection: Beaufort, 1972; Beaufort Inlet-Bogue Inlet, 1965-1966; Bodie Island, 1970-1971; Bogue Inlet-Moore Inlet, 1965-1972 (Box 145)
    - Beach Erosion and Hurricane Protection: Brunswick Co. Beaches, 1958-1972, 2 folders (Box 145)
    - Beach Erosion and Hurricane Protection: Cape Hatteras, 1969-1972; Cape Lookout, 1967-1972 (Box 146)
    - Beach Erosion and Hurricane Protection: Carolina Beach and vicinity, 1959-1972 (Box 146)
    - Beach Erosion and Hurricane Protection: Eastern N.C., 1965-1972; Ft. Fisher, 1964-1971; Ft. Macon/Atlantic Beach, 1962-1972; Hatteras to Va. State Line, 1965-1968 (Box 146)
    - Beach Erosion and Hurricane Protection: Kure Beach, 1969; Mainland Areas of N.C., 1965-1966; New Bern and vicinity, 1963-1969; North River Dike, 1970-1971; Okracoke Inlet to Beaufort Inlet, 1965-1968 (Box 146)
    - Beach Erosion and Hurricane Protection: Okracoke Inlet to Bogue Inlet, 1964-1965; Okracoke Island, 1960- 1972; Okracoke Island to Cape Lookout, 1960-1969 (Box 146)
    - Beach Erosion and Hurricane Protection: Outer Banks, 1971-1972; Pamlico Co. (Oriental), 1958-1959; Pamlico River, 1967-1972; Topsail Beach and Surf City, 1970-1971; Washington, NC and vicinity, 1966-1972 (Box 146)
    - Beach Erosion and Hurricane Protection: Wrightsville Beach 1961-1972 (Box 147)
    - Federal Highway Program, 1958-1961, 1964 (Box 147)
    - Flood Control: Adkins Branch (Lenoir Co.), 1966-1971; Beech Creek Dam (Sanford), 1961; Benaja Station (Cape Fear Basin), 1964-1965; Beulahtown Dam (Neuse Basin), 1966-1971; Black River (Harnett Co.), 1961- 1968; Black River (Sampson and Pender Co.), 1966-1967; Broad Creek (Beaufort Co.), 1963-1966; Buck Creek, 1966-1970; Buckhorn Dam (Neuse Basin), 1966-1972 (Box 147)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Correspondence, 1957-1962 Nov., 3 folders (Box 147)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Correspondence, 1963-1971, 6 folders (Box 148)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Correspondence, (pro-New Hope Dam), 1961-1966 (Box 149)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Correspondence, (anti-New Hope Dam), 1962-1964 (Box 149)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Mailing Lists, 1957-1964, 1970-1972 and undated (Box 149)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Maps, 1960-1968 (Box 149)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Resolutions, 1962-1963 (Box 149)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Statements, memos, etc., 1955-1962 (Box 149)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Statements, memos, etc. 1963-1964, 1969-1972 and undated (Box 150)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Studies and documents (Record of Public Hearing), 1957 (Box 150)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Studies and documents (Joint Land and Water Resources Study) 1957 (Box 150)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Studies and documents, 1957-1959 (Box 150)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Studies and documents (Jt. Report of Land and Water Resources Study), 1961 (2 volumes) (Box 151)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Studies and documents (Comprehensive Report of Cape Fear River Basin), 1961-1962 (2 volumes and 2 addenda) (Box 151)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Studies and documents, 1962-1963, 1967 (Box 151)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Studies and documents, 1968-1971 May (Box 151)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Studies and documents, 1971 June - 1972 (Box 152)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Studies and documents (Environmental Impact Statement), 1971 (3 volumes) (Box 152)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Randleman and Howard's Mill Dams, 1958-1960, 1964-1972, 2 folders (Box 153)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Upper Basin 1966-1972 (Box 153)
    - Flood Control: Cape Fear River Basin: Clippings, 1956-1958, 1961-1972, 3 folders (Box 153)
    - Flood Control: Clinchfield Dam, 1967-1971 (Box 153)
    - Flood Control: Clinchfield Dam, 1972 May-Oct., 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Flood Control: Collie Swamp, 1971-1972; Ellerbee Creek, 1959; Fairfield Drainage, 1958 (Box 54)
    - Flood Control: Falls of the Neuse, 1967-1972, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Flood Control: First Broad River, 1971-1972; Gap Way Swamp, 1963-1966; Greater Gaston Shoals, 1972; Haw River, 1964-1968; Hyde County Dike, 1968-1971 (Box 54)
    - Flood Control: Keowee-Toxaway Project (Duke Power Co.), 1965-1969 (Box 54)
    - Flood Control: John H. Kerr Reservoir, 1952-1964, 1968-1972, 3 folders (Box 155)
    - Flood Control: Lumber River, 1961-1971; Lyon Swamp, 1960; Mill Creek, 1964-1971 (Box 155)
    - Flood Control: Neuse River (incl. Public Hearing record), 1932, 1956-1957 (1 folder and 1 volume) (Box 155)
    - Flood Control: Neuse River, 1958-1972, 5 folders (Box 156)
    - Flood Control: New River/Kanawha Basin, 1959, 1963-1964 (Box 156)
    - Flood Control: New River/Kanawha Basin, 1965-1967, 5 folders (Box 157)
    - Flood Control: New River/Kanawha Basin, 1968-1971 May, 5 folders (Box 158)
    - Flood Control: New River/Kanawha Basin, 1971 Jun.- 1972, 3 folders (Box 159)
    - Flood Control: New River/Kanawha Basin (Appalachian Power Co.), 1967-1971 (Box 159)
    - Flood Control: New River/Kanawha Basin (Clippings), 1959, 1963-1972 (Box 159)
    - Flood Control: Northeast Cape Fear River, 1965-1971; Northeastern North Carolina Project, 1963-1971 (Box 159)
    - Flood Control: Pamlico River Causeway, 1966-1971; Pantego and Cucklers Creeks, 1959-1960; Perquimas River, 1961 and 1965; Roanoke River, 1961-1968 (Box 160)
    - Flood Control: Santee River, 1961-1967 (Box 160)
    - Flood Control: Tar-Pamlico River, 1962-1971 (Box 160)
    - Flood Control: Thoroughfare Swamp, 1963-1971; Toisnot Swamp 1959; Tranters Creek, 1963-1971; Trent River, 1964-1967 (Box 160)
    - Flood Control: Upper French Broad River, 1958 and 1965 Mar.-Dec., 2 folders (Box 160)
    - Flood Control: Upper French Broad River, 1966-1970 Oct., 5 folders (Box 161)
    - Flood Control: Upper French Broad River, 1970 Oct.- 1971 Oct., 5 folders (Box 162)
    - Flood Control: Upper French Broad River, 1971 Nov.- Dec. (Box 163)
    - Flood Control: Upper French Broad River: "Record of Public Hearing on the Proposed Mills River Project," 1971 (2 volumes) (Box 163)
    - Flood Control: Upper French Broad River, 1972 (Box 164)
    - Flood Control: Upper French Broad River (Clippings), 1965-1972 (Box 164)
    - Flood Control: Waccamaw River, 1959-1971 (Box 164)